# **Daniel Newton**

# Data Analyst

615-479-8624

d.curtis.newton@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-newton-607427100/

#### MY PURPOSE and MISSION

Hungry to find my first position where I can blend my love of analytics, number crunching, streamlining efficient processes and fast-paced work environments with a high-sense-of-urgency. Previous experience include: technical recruiting, direct sales, journalism, restaurant management.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Nashville Software School - Data Analyst

July 2020 - Current

- Undertook a 6 month program to learn the skills necessary to transition into data analytics
- Skills learned include: SQL (PostGres), Python, Excel (pivot tables, vlookup, etc), Power BI, Tableau and more
- Worked on multiple group and individual projects, including work presented to and used by local Government officials.

#### **IQTalent Partners** - Recruiting Engagement Leader

June 2018 - Current

- Leading a small team of recruiters as we hire technical and sales/marketing roles across the world for startups.
- Experience primarily with startups in the SaaS and SDK industry.
- Key member of test groups that provide feedback and alpha/beta testing for newly built
  internal tools, including company leadership in assisting data migration as well as analysis
  of new processes being considered for best practices.
- Experience speaking with C-Level and hiring teams for setting directions and expectations in hiring strategies for key roles.

#### Edley's BBQ - Assistant Catering Director / Store Management

February 2016 - Current (part time)

- Directing large and small crews in multiple settings, both in-store and out-of-store.
- Built systems to increase productivity by having accurate projections and best practices.
- Saw doubling catering profits over two years in leadership.
- Aided in training and assisting in opening the company's first two locations outside of Nashville

## **EDUCATION**

Nashville Software School, Nashville TN - Data Analytics Bootcamp

July 2020 - January 2021

# **Austin Peay State University, Clarksville TN** - B.S. in Economics

September 2010 - August 2014

- Member of the Kappa Sigma fraternity where I held the titles of: President, Treasurer and Head of Recruitment. Was awarded scholarships because of my fraternal work and academic success.
- Former Sports Editor of APSU's student newspaper, "The All-State."

## **PROJECTS**